Guide to the Somalia Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Somalia collection
1904-2005
MS 1542
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.77
(8 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material and photographs relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Somalia.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically, with photographs last. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material and photographs relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Somalia.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
British Somaliland; Somalia -- Description and travel; Somalia -- Economic conditions; Somalia -- Politics and government; Somalia -- Social conditions; United Liberation Front of Western Somalia
- Inventory
  - Liberal Publication Department: newsbrief, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, 1964, 1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ministry of Information: magazines, newspapers, 1964, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Osman, Aden Abdulla, presidential address, 1964 December 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Opinion": publication of the Somalia Students Association (in U.S.A.), 1965 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Il Combattente": organo del Comando Esercito, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Somalia National Academy: newsletter (Arabic), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Barre, Jaalle Abdurahman Jama, PhD, Minister of Foreign Affairs: speeches, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Halgan": publication of the Western Social Liberation Front, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Al-Nidal: bulletin of the United Liberation Front of Western Somalia, 1975 Sep/October, 1977 Aug, [1977?] Sep/October (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Somali Liberation Fronts (SALF): bulletins, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Somali Revolutionary Socialist Party (SRSP): publication, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - A Sketch of Somalia and its People, by G. J. R. Tod, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Anglo-Somali Society: journals, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Warsidaha Somaliland, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Africa Centre: printed materials, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Somali Poetry": flyer of the African-American Institute (AAI), undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Somali Relief Fund: pamphlet, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photograph from exhibit entitled "What Helps?", 1993 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Additional Material, Accession 1995-M-200
  - Additional printed materials, 1954, 1973, 1997 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 2002-M-067
  - "Barren God-Forsaken Somaliland," by Kenneth Rossi [photocopy of manuscript], 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
  - "A Photographic Record of British Somaliland, 1945-1948..." [photograph album in two volumes, compiled by Kenneth Rossi], 1947 (Box 2, Folder 4 - 5)
- Additional Material, 1981, 1989, 1993; Accession 2006-M-089
  - Buugga Kacaanka, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Out of Africa," by Ron Dunsky, MacNeil/Lehrer Newshour Newsprint, 1993 summer (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Somali Horizon, no. 11, magazine of the Somali National Movement, U.S. Branch, 1989 January-March (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, 1973-1992; Accession 2011-M-028
  - Cilmiga Olell (Tusmada Cilmiga), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mogadishu Pan-African Film Symposium (MOGPAFIS), information packet, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - New Era: WAAGA CUSBA, no. 5, Ministry of Information and National Guidance, 1973 June (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - S.I.M. Community Development report, 1975 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Compiled by the Security in Mobility (S.I.M.) partnership.
  - SOMRA: The Somalis: An Invisible Community in Crisis, information packet, 1992
    Compiled by the Somali Relief Association (UK).
- Additional Material, 1966-circa 2005; Accession 2015-M-001; 2.02
  - Printed material, 1966-1983? (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Poster, Circa 2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)